Guide to the Marshall T. Meyer Papers, 1902-2004 and undated, bulk 1984-1993 RL.00895
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Research Files Series, 1902-1993 and undated, bulk 1985-1993, 33 boxes
  - Organizations Subseries, 1902-1993 and undated, bulk 1985-1993, 22 boxes
    - Archives of Conservative Judaism, 1986 (Box 24)
    - Aspen Institute, 1992 (Box 24)
    - Ben-Gurion University, 1987-1991 (Box 24)
    - Bet El, 1961-1992, 1-2 of 5 folders (Box 24)
    - Bet El, 1961-1992, 3-5 of 5 folders (Box 25)
    - Bet El - Buenos Aires, 1981-1988 (Box 25)
    - Bet El - Majane Ramah, 1959-1984 (Box 25)
    - Bet El Seminario, 1986 (Box 25)
    - Bet El - Spanish, 1959, 1973-1987 and undated, 1 of 2 folders (Box 25)
    - Bet El - Spanish, 1959, 1973-1987 and undated, 2 of 2 folders (Box 25)
    - B'nai B'rith, 1986-1993 (Box 25)
    - B'nai Jeshurun, 1985-1992, 3 folders (Box 26)
    - B'nai Jeshurun Shelter Program, 1988-1989 (Box 26)
    - Brandeis-Bardin Institute, 1971-1973, 1984-1990 (Box 26)
    - Brandeis - Think Tank on Congregational Affiliation, 1992 (Box 26)
    - Brooklyn Union of American-Hebrew Congregations, 1964-1974, 3 folders (Box 26)
    - B'Tselem, 1990 (Box 26)
    - Building Communities Through Diversity, 1990 (Box 26)
    - Caanan Baptist Church - Reverend Wyatt T. Walker, 1990 (Box 26)
    - Cabell Brand Association, 1987-1988 (Box 26)
    - Camera News Incorporated, 1986 (Box 26)
    - Camp Ramah, USA, 1960-1987 (Box 26)
    - The Cathedral of St. John the Divine, 1986-1989 and undated (Box 27)
    - Center for Inter-American Relations, 1987 (Box 27)
    - Center for Jewish Renewal, 1989 (Box 27)
    - Center on Violence and Human Survival - John Jay College, 1987-1990, and undated (Box 27)
    - Central American Refugee Center, 1990 (Box 27)
    - Christianity and Crisis, 1991-1992 (Box 27)
    - Coalition for a Nuclear-Free Harbor, 1987-1990 (Box 27)
    - Coalition for the Homeless, 1987-1990 (Box 27)
    - Comunidad Bet El, 1987-1990, 2 folders (Box 27)
    - Committee on Jewish Law, 1946-1978 and undated, 2 folders (Box 27)
    - Conference on Judaism in Rural New England, 1984-1986 (Box 27)
    - Congregacion Israelita, 1959-1963 (Box 27)
    - Consumers Union, 1987 (Box 28)
    - Costa Rica Instituto Interamericano de Derechos Humanos, 1980-1984 (Box 28)
    - Council of Churches of the City of New York, 1987 (Box 28)
    - Council for a Parliament of the World's Religions, 1993 (Box 28)
    - Dartmouth, 1989-1993, 2 folders (Box 28)
    - Dartmouth Alumni Association, 1985-1993, 2 folders (Box 28)
    - Dartmouth Center for Jewish Life, 1993 (Box 28)
    - Dartmouth; Eugen Rosenstock-Huessy Centennial, 1988 (Box 28)
    - Dartmouth Fall, 1991, 2 folders (Box 28)
    - Day of the African Child, 1993 (Box 29)
    - East Harlem Interfaith Welfare Committee, 1988-1989 (Box 29)
    - Editorial Paidos, 1966-1970 (Box 29)
    - Farrar, Straus, and Giroux, 1986-1987 (Box 29)
    - Federation of Jewish Philanthropies of New York, 1985-1990, 2 folders (Box 29)
    - Fellowship of Reconciliation, 1989-1990 (Box 29)
    - Feria del Libro, 1984-1986 (Box 29)
    - First International Network for Democracy - Shula Koenig, 1987 (Box 29)
    - The Free Press, 1985-1986 (Box 29)
    - Freedom, Justice, and Peace Society, 1990-1992 (Box 29)
    - Friends of Al'Haq - Law in the Service of Man, 1989 (Box 29)
    - Friends of the Forum for Social and Economic Policy in Israel, 1988 (Box 29)
    - Friends of Peace Now, 1987-1989 (Box 29)
    - Foundation for Masorti Judaism, 1990 (Box 29)
    - Gay Men's Health Crisis, 1990 (Box 29)
    - Givat Haviva, 1988-1992 (Box 29)
    - Global Forum of Spiritual and Parliamentary Leaders on Human Survival, 1988-1990 (Box 29)
    - Golda Meir Association, 1988 (Box 29)
    - Gross - Weston, 1986 (Box 29)
    - Harvard Divinity School, 1992, 1 of 4 folders (Box 29)
    - Harvard Divinity School, 1992, 2-4 of 4 folders (Box 30)
    - Harvard - Merrill Scholarship, 1991 (Box 30)
    - Hebrew Free Burial Association, 1992-1993 (Box 30)
    - Hebrew Union College, 1984-1991 (Box 30)
    - Homes for the Homeless, 1986-1991 (Box 30)
    - Homes for the Homeless - St. John the Divine, 1985-1987 and undated (Box 30)
    - Hope for Peace in Central America, 1986 (Box 30)
    - Human Rights Watch, 1988-1992, 2 folders (Box 30)
    - Indra's Net, 1990 (Box 30)
    - Institute for Jewish Renewal, 1990 (Box 30)
    - Interfaith, 1992-1993 and undated (Box 31)
    - Interfaith Association on Homelessness and Housing, 1987-1992 (Box 31)
    - Interfaith Center on Corporate Responsibility, 1986-1990 (Box 31)
    - The International Center - Clementia, 1989-1990 (Box 31)
    - International Center for Peace in the Middle East, 1985-1992, 4 folders (Box 31)
    - International Council of Christians and Jews, 1990-1991 (Box 31)
    - International Jewish Peace Union, 1990-1991 (Box 31)
    - International Support Group of the Israeli Palestine Center for Research and Information, 1991 (Box 31)
    - Israel Cancer Association, 1990 (Box 31)
    - Israel Interfaith Association, 1987-1989 (Box 31)
    - Israel-Palestine Center for Research and Information, 1989-1991 (Box 31)
    - Israeli Association for the Study of Latin American Jewry, 1989-1990 (Box 31)
    - Israeli Civil Rights and Peace, 1992 (Box 31)
    - Jewish Association for Services for the Aged, 1986 (Box 31)
    - Jewish Center for Learning and Leadership, 1985-1988 (Box 31)
    - Jewish Committee on the Middle East, 1988-1990 (Box 31)
    - Jewish Community Center of the Upper Westside, 1991 (Box 32)
    - Jewish Community Relations Council, 1986-1987 (Box 32)
    - Jewish Currents, 1986-1987 (Box 32)
    - Jewish Educators Assembly, 1987 (Box 32)
    - Jewish Family and Children's Services, 1990 (Box 32)
    - Jewish Federation of Metropolitan Chicago, 1992 (Box 32)
    - Jewish Frontier, 1989 (Box 32)
    - Jewish Fund for Justice, 1986-1991, 2 folders (Box 32)
    - Jewish Historical Society of New York, 1990 (Box 32)
    - Jewish Labor Committee, 1992 (Box 32)
    - Jewish Peace Fellowship, 1985 (Box 32)
    - Jewish Peace Lobby, 1989-1992 (Box 32)
    - Jewish Publication Society, 1988 (Box 32)
    - Jewish Spectator, 1989-1990 (Box 32)
    - Jewish Theological Seminary, 1985-1993, 5 folders (Box 32)
    - Jewish Theological Seminary - Academic Articles, 1902, 1955-1970, 1983-1985, 2 folders (Box 33)
    - Jewish Theological Seminary Centennial, 1984-1988 (Box 33)
    - Jewish Theological Seminary - Centennial Medal to Raul Alfonsin, 1985 (Box 33)
    - Jews for Radical Justice, 1990-1993 (Box 33)
    - Joint Distribution Committee, 1986-1989, 2 folders (Box 33)
    - Jubilee - Christians for Justice Action, 1993 (Box 33)
    - Latin American Jewish Studies, 1985-1990 (Box 33)
    - Latin American Report, 1984-1990 (Box 33)
    - Lehrhaus, 1986-1987 (Box 34)
    - Mazon, 1988-1992 (Box 34)
    - Miscellaneous Jewish Organizations, 1986-1991 (Box 34)
    - Montgomery Fellow, 1990-1991 (Box 34)
    - National Agenda for Peace in El Salvador, 1990 (Box 34)
    - National Council on Islamic Affairs, 1990 (Box 34)
    - National Jewish Community Relations Advisory Council, 1992 (Box 34)
    - National Jewish Democratic Council, 1992 (Box 34)
    - Nest Foundation, 1989 (Box 34)
    - New Israel Fund, 1984-1991, 2 folders (Box 34)
    - New Jewish Agenda, 1984-1991, 1-3 of 7 folders (Box 34)
    - New Jewish Agenda, 1984-1991, 4-7 of 7 folders (Box 35)
    - New York City Civil Rights Coalition, 1989 (Box 35)
    - New York City Coalition for Women's Mental Health, 1988 (Box 35)
    - New York City Interfaith Council, 1989 (Box 35)
    - New York City Labor Religion Coalition, 1987-1990 (Box 35)
    - New York State National Abortion Right's Action League, 1988-1990 (Box 35)
    - Norwich Free Academy, 1990 (Box 35)
    - Organization for Rehabilitation Through Training, 1986-1989 (Box 35)
    - Oxford Centre for Post-Graduate Hebrew Studies, 1986 (Box 35)
    - Parliamentary Earth Summit - Rio de Janeiro, 1992 (Box 35)
    - Partnership for the Homeless, 1993 (Box 35)
    - Paul Moore Conference on Religion and Human Rights, 1993 (Box 35)
    - Peace Now, 1984-1992 (Box 35)
    - Peace with Justice Week, 1992 (Box 35)
    - Pew Charitable Trust, 1992 (Box 35)
    - Rally for Peace, 1988 (Box 35)
    - Religious Leaders Media Project, 1985-1988 (Box 35)
    - The Resource Center, 1990-1992 (Box 35)
    - Rich Foundation Report, 1988-1990 (Box 35)
    - Seminario Rabinico Latinamericano, 1962-1993, 1 of 14 folders (Box 35)
    - Seminario Rabinico Latinamericano, 1962-1993, 2-12 of 14 folders (Box 36)
    - Seminario Rabinico Latinamericano, 1962-1993, 13-14 of 14 folders (Box 37)
    - Seminario Rabinico - Semana de Festejos, 1993 (Box 37)
    - The Shalom Center, Pennsylvania, 1989-1991 (Box 37)
    - Sing Sing Prison, 1990 (Box 37)
    - Smithtown, 1956-1957 (Box 37)
    - Social Action, 1987-1990 (Box 37)
    - St. John the Divine Cathedral Church, 1986-1992 (Box 37)
    - Street Aid, 1989-1990 (Box 37)
    - Sudbury Valley School, 1985-1986 and undated (Box 37)
    - Synagogue Council of America, 1984-1990 (Box 37)
    - Temple of Understanding, 1964, 1975, 1985-1993, 1-2 of 8 folders (Box 37)
    - Temple of Understanding, 1964, 1975, 1985-1993, 3-8 of 8 folders (Box 38)
    - Tikkun, 1985-1992 (Box 38)
    - Tikkun Olam Dialogue Series, 1987-1988 (Box 38)
    - Tucker Foundation, Dartmouth College, 1993 (Box 38)
    - Tucker Foundation, 1989-1993, 1 of 2 folders (Box 38)
    - Tucker Foundation, 1989-1993, 2 of 2 folders (Box 39)
    - United Jewish Appeal, 1985-1990 (Box 39)
    - United Synagogue of America, 1986-1991 (Box 39)
    - University of Judaism, 1983-1995, 2 folders (Box 39)
    - University of Judaism - Arts Center, 1984-1985 (Box 39)
    - University of Nebraska at Omaha, 1990 (Box 39)
    - U.S. Interreligious Committee for Peace in the Middle East, 1987-1993, 1-4 of 7 folders (Box 39)
    - U.S. Interreligious Committee for Peace in the Middle East, 1987-1993, 5-7 of 7 folders (Box 40)
    - Vision Interfaith Satellite Network, 1990 (Box 40)
    - The Wannsee Conference, 1989 (Box 40)
    - War and Peace, 1991-1993 (Box 40)
    - Washington Office on Latin America (WOLA), 1983-1987 (Box 40)
    - Wednesday Morning Group, 1986-1993, 2 folders (Box 40)
    - Wellfleet Conference, 1987-1990 (Box 40)
    - Westside Jewish Community Council, 1985-1987, 1996 (Box 40)
    - WETA FM91, 1988-1989 (Box 40)
    - White Plains, 1958-1960 and undated (Box 40)
    - Who's Who, 1978-1979, 1990-1993 (Box 40)
    - Who's Who in Religion - America, 1991-1993 (Box 40)
    - Witness for Peace, 1986-1987 (Box 40)
    - World Council of Churches, Canberra 1991, 1991 (Box 40)
    - World Council of Churches, Hong Kong, 1990 (Box 40)
    - World Council of Churches, 1964, 1990-1993, 5 folders (Box 41)
    - World Council for Progressive Judaism, 1987-1991 (Box 41)
    - World Council of Synagogues, 1968-1990 (Box 41)
    - World Wings, 1989 (Box 41)
    - Yivo, 1990 (Box 41)
    - Zahavi, 1988 (Box 41)
    - Zen Community of New York, 1987-1991 (Box 41)
  - People Subseries, 1926-2002 and undated, 5 boxes
    Contains files organized alphabetically by the names of individuals or social groups. Many of those listed are rabbis or are affiliated with human rights and humanitarian efforts.
    - 17th Anniversary Notes, undated (Box 41)
    - African-Americans and Jews, 1992 (Box 41)
    - Marcos Aguinis, 1970-1971, 1983-1992, 2 folders (Box 42)
    - Jacob Agus, 1966-1969, 1985, and undated (Box 42)
    - Antisemitism in Latin America, 1983-1986 and undated (Box 42)
    - Barcelona Jewish Community, undated (Box 42)
    - Leonard Bernstein, 1990-1993 (Box 42)
    - Carolina Biquard, 1991-1992 (Box 42)
    - Robert Bork, 1987 (Box 42)
    - Born Again Christians, 1987 (Box 42)
    - Fernando Arturo Branca, 1983-1988 (Box 42)
    - Marcelo Bronstein, 1989-1991 (Box 42)
    - Martin Buber - Writings and Notes, 1951-1957, 1976, 1988 (Box 42)
    - Nadav Caine, 1993 (Box 42)
    - William Sloane Coffin, 1990 (Box 42)
    - Arthur A. Cohen, undated (Box 42)
    - Doctor Gerson Cohen, 1984-1991 (Box 42)
    - Sally Cowal, 1992 (Box 42)
    - Israel Davidson, 1934-1939, 1947 and undated (Box 42)
    - David Dinkins, Edward Koch, 1987-1991 (Box 42)
    - Ernest Dube, 1983-1987 and undated (Box 43)
    - Joseph Eger, 1980-1986 (Box 43)
    - Jacobo Finkelstein, 1988-1989 (Box 43)
    - Frederick Franck, 1991 (Box 43)
    - Doctor Reuven Gal, 1991-1992 (Box 43)
    - Martin Garbus, 1990 (Box 43)
    - Janet A. Geller, 1993 (Box 43)
    - Osvaldo Golijov, 1994 (Box 43)
    - Ethan Gologar, 1993 (Box 43)
    - Daniel Greensberg, 1966 (Box 43)
    - Dr. Mario Handlarz, 1960-1987 (Box 43)
    - Raymond Helmick, 1991 (Box 43)
    - Dr. A. J. Heschel, 1973, 1988-1992 and undated (Box 43)
    - Abraham Heschel, 1977, 1987 and undated, 2 folders (Box 43)
    - Jacques J. Hess, 1986-1988 (Box 43)
    - Eugen Rosenstock Huessy (1-4 of 5 folders), 1926, 1937-1958, 1973, 1982-1990 and undated (Box 43)
    - Eugen Rosenstock Huessy (5 of 5 folders), 1926, 1937-1958, 1973, 1982-1990 and undated (Box 44)
    - Harold B. Jacobsohn, 1969, 1987 (Box 44)
    - Luis Jaimovich, 1992 (Box 44)
    - Jews by Choice, 1986 (Box 44)
    - Martin Kalmanoff, 1993 (Box 44)
    - Pedro Kanof, 1991-1992 (Box 44)
    - Edward Kaplan, 1991-1993 (Box 44)
    - Ely Kaufman, 1991-1993 (Box 44)
    - Wolfe Kellman, 1990-1991 (Box 44)
    - Dr. Martin Luther King, 1987-1991 (Box 44)
    - Jorge Leyt, 1991 (Box 44)
    - Allan Long, 1993 (Box 44)
    - Allan Long, 1993 (Box 44)
    - Arkady and Elena Mai, 1989-1990 (Box 44)
    - Ruth Messinger, 1988 (Box 44)
    - Marshall T. Meyer - Argentine Trip, 1990 (Box 44)
    - Marshall T. Meyer - Homiletics, 1963-1964 (Box 44)
    - George Allen Morgan, 1986 and undated (Box 44)
    - Meyers Research Notes, 1976-1988 and undated (Box 44)
    - Eric Meyers, 1986 (Box 44)
    - Professor Eric Mark Meyers, 1982-1990 (Box 44)
    - Miscellaneous Professional Jews/Judaism, 1986-1993 (Box 45)
    - Reinhold Niebuhr, 1958 (Box 45)
    - Jacob Neusner, 1990-1993 (Box 45)
    - Pamela Oline, 1990-1992 (Box 45)
    - Rabino Plavnick, 1988 and undated, 2 folders (Box 45)
    - Doctor German A. Politzer, 1989-1992 (Box 45)
    - Rabbi's Sermons, 1954, 1969 and undated (Box 45)
    - Theodore Riegel, 1993 and undated (Box 45)
    - Susan Rosenberg, Nina Rosenblum, 1987-1988 (Box 45)
    - Elinor Ross, 1976-1985 (Box 45)
    - Guillermo Schlesinger, 1959 (Box 45)
    - Ismar Schorsch, 1992-1993 (Box 45)
    - Stanley Sheinbaum, 1985-1987 (Box 45)
    - Don Shriver, 1991 (Box 45)
    - Osvaldo Sivak, 1981-1987 (Box 45)
    - Robert Spero, 1988-1993 (Box 45)
    - Harold Ticktin, 1981-1988, and undated (Box 45)
    - Adolfo Weil (Bet El) versus Nissim Elnecave Y La Luz, 1972 (Box 46)
    - Erna Weill, 1975 (Box 46)
    - Eugene Weiner, 1974, 1990-1991 and undated (Box 46)
    - Ted Weiss, 1985-1989 (Box 46)
    - Yo'Av Karny, 1993 (Box 46)
  - Subjects Subseries, 1956-1994 and undated, 3 boxes
    Contain articles and other sources of information regarding various subjects of interest or relation to Meyer. Many of these deal with human rights and humanitarian issues, or with Judaism; formats include speeches, newspaper and magazine articles, and lectures regarding the specific subjects. Arranged alphabetically by folder title.
    - Adoption, 1986-1989 (Box 46)
    - AIDS, 1992 (Box 46)
    - Anti-nuclear legislation, undated (Box 46)
    - Anti-semitism, 1953, 1982-1988 (Box 46)
    - Anti-war declarations, 1991 (Box 46)
    - Curriculum for congregational schools, 1957 (Box 46)
    - Community resources - social services, 1985 (Box 46)
    - Ecumenical affairs, 1985-1987 (Box 46)
    - Gay and lesbian youth, 1985-1991 (Box 46)
    - Gays and homosexuality, 1992-1993 (Box 46)
    - Holocaust, 1983-1987 (Box 46)
    - Homeless, 1993 and undated (Box 46)
    - Homeless and housing, 1985-1987 (Box 46)
    - Homelessness, 1987-1988 (Box 46)
    - Homiletics, 1988 and undated (Box 46)
    - Homosexuality, 1990-1993, 1 of 3 folders (Box 46)
    - Homosexuality, 1990-1993, 2-3 of 3 folders (Box 47)
    - Immigrants and refugees, 1985 (Box 47)
    - Immigrant visa program, 1991 (Box 47)
    - Interfaith, 1986-1991 (Box 47)
    - Interfaith affairs, 1956, 1983-1993 (Box 47)
    - Israel Bill of Rights, 1986-1989 (Box 47)
    - Israel bonds, 1988-1993 (Box 47)
    - Jewish college students, 1966 (Box 47)
    - Jewish singles, 1985 (Box 47)
    - Jews and smoking, 1992 (Box 47)
    - Jewish poverty, 1989 (Box 47)
    - Latin American Jewry, 1964-1972, 1981, 1991 (Box 47)
    - Liturgy, 1967-1985 (Box 47)
    - Liberation theology, 1988 (Box 47)
    - Messianism, 1985 and undated (Box 47)
    - Miscellaneous research notes, 1977-1984, 1993 and undated (Box 48)
    - New York City Social Problems, 1984-1988 (Box 48)
    - Nuclear issues, 1984-1988 (Box 48)
    - Order of the Liberator San Martin, 1984 (Box 48)
    - Peace organizations, undated (Box 48)
    - Presidential matters, 1990 (Box 48)
    - Prisons in New York, 1988 (Box 48)
    - Rabbinical school statistics, undated (Box 48)
    - Reformed Judaism, 1989-1990 (Box 48)
    - Religions services in Spanish, 1959, 1971-1991 (Box 48)
    - Sanctuary Movement, 1984-1988 (Box 48)
    - Social Action, 1985-1987 (Box 48)
    - Soviet Jewry, 1987-1990, 2 folders (Box 48)
    - Terrorism, undated (Box 48)
    - Yiddish Gauchos, 1989 (Box 48)
- Printed Material Series, 1919-2001 and undated, 5 boxes
  Contains printed material collected by Meyer over the span of his career. Formats include magazines, newspapers, clippings, reports, monographs, and photocopies. Material is in English, Spanish, and Hebrew.
  The series has been organized into two sections. Jewish Intellectual Thought (Boxes 49-50) contains publications by such Jewish intellectuals as Louis Finkelstein, Daniel Greenberg, Philip Segal and others. Jewish Life (Boxes 51-53) contains material relating to Latin American Jews, Israel, and Jewish law and ethics. The end of this section (Box 53) contains material about Meyer as well as miscellaneous publications.
  - Printed material, 1919-2001, 4 boxes (Box 49-53)
- Teaching Material Series, 1965-1997, 2 boxes
  Material related to Meyer's lectures and teaching on Jewish theology, Jewish culture, human rights in Argentina, and the "disappeared" (Meyer lectured at various institutions around the world including USA, Israel, and Latin America). Files may contain transcripts or lecture notes, as well as correspondence, printed material, programs, and ephemera. Note: there may be some duplication of material found in the Writings and Speeches Series. Some transcriptions of Meyer's lectures and courses can also be found in the Electronic Files Series.
  - Teaching material, 1965-1997, 2 boxes (Box 54-55)
- Personal Files Series, 1949-1993 and undated, 10 boxes, 1 oversize box
  Meyer's personal files contain early schoolwork, appointment books, memorabilia, and items of biographical interest. See also oversize materials section (Box 84).
  - Photos, memorabilia, engagements [Oversized items removed to box 84], 1 box (Box 56)
  - Appointment books, 1982-1984,1986-1989,1991-1993 (Box 57)
  - Educational material, 1949-1959, 1961-1974, 5 boxes (Box 58-62)
    Comprises Meyer's schoolwork from Dartmouth and the Jewish Theological Seminary of America, organized by course and subject. Files are grouped by institution.
  - Biographical material, 1982-1993, 3 boxes (Box 63-65)
    Contains interviews with and articles about Meyer. Material is international in scope and includes items in English and Spanish, as well as some German, Hebrew, and Russian.
- Audiovisual Material Series, 14 boxes
  Conditions Governing Access note
  Originals of video and audiotapes are closed to use. Digital access copies are available for the videos listed below, by requesting the digital set RL00895-SET-0001.
  Contains both audio and video recordings of Meyer's public appearances and interviews. Videos (boxes 70-73) consist of various public appearances, sermons, ceremonies, and interviews of Meyer. Also includes a few broadcasts relating to human rights issues. Sound recordings on audio cassettes and micro-cassettes (boxes 70-79) are arranged in three sections: lectures include "the Prophets", "A.J. Heschel", "Gnosticism" and others, dating 1989-1993; religious services include sermons, Yom Kippur, and Rosh Hashana services at B'nai Jeshurn, dating from 1988-1992; and various appearances and addresses include Shabbat with Nelson Mandela, talks on human rights, talks in Argentina, an oral history interview, and others, dating from 1989-1993. Tape-counter numbers and summaries of some of the audio cassettes can be found in Disk 018 of the Electronic Files Series.
  Digital access copies are available for the following titles by requesting the digital set RL00895-SET-0001:
  "A Dirty War," n.d.
  "Australian 60 Minutes," n.d.
  Doctorado Honoris Causa (UBA) Cena Homenaje 30 Aniversario, n.d.
  "In Love and Friendship," n.d.
  Judaism, Part II - "In Search of Reconciliation," n.d.
  "L'Chayim," n.d.
  "Para Vivir Aqui," Video de Fundacion Memoria Connadep/Enevista, n.d.
  "Race Relations," Charlie Rose, n.d.
  "When Bad Things Happen to Good People," n.d.
  Late Night America, PBS-TV, 1985 Jul. 18
  "Religion and Social Activism," The Open Mind, 1987 Nov. 22
  Rosh Hashanah 5752, 1991
  "Why and How to Be an Activist," 1991 Oct. 17
  Interview with Rabbi Marshall T. Meyer, 1992
  Inteview with Rabbi Marshall Meyer conducted by Jonathan Perlman, 1992 May 29
  "A Conversation on Prayer," Rabbi Marshall T. Meyer and Rabbi Rolando Matalon, 1993 Oct. 15
  WNYC 1994, Oct.
  "A Dirty War," 1994 Dec. 8
  BJ Images, Congegration B'nai Jeshurun Archives, 1994-1995
  Programo Mosaigo, 1996 Mar. 23
  Marshall Meyer Compilation, 1996 Dec.
  Rabbi Marshall T. Meyer, 1997
  "No Right To Be Silent," 1998 Jan. 12
  - Video Cassettes, 4 boxes (Box 66-69, Digital-materials RL00895-SET-0001)
  - Audio Recordings, 10 boxes (Box 70-79)
- Condolences Series, 1993-1994, 3 boxes
  Cards and notes expressing sympathy on Meyer's death. Many of these contain testimonials and reminiscences of his role as rabbi and activist.
  - Condolences, 1993-1994 (Box 80-82)
- Electronic Files Series, 1952-1995 and undated, Approximately 850 electronic files extracted from 32 floppy diskettes and 3 optical discs.